EMILIE GERBER

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- 503.475.3520
- emiliegerberharris@gmail.com
- Seattle, WA
- in /in/emiliegerber
- emiliegerber.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Art Drawing / Painting / Print

Portland State University 2006 - 2008

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages:

JavaScript, Ruby, HTML5, CSS **Frameworks**:

Node.JS, Express, Rails,

AngularJS

Database Tools:

SQL, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Active Records **Other**: jQuery, AJAX, JSON, Bootstrap, Heroku, AWS, Drupal, SalesForce, Google Analytics

PROFILE

I am a front-end web developer with former marketing and graphic design experience. I enjoy creating websites that are a seamless balance of aesthetics, usability and quality to provide the best user experience. Drawing from my past experiences as an Account Manager and Marketing Coordinator, I close the gap between business requirements and the customer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Part-time | What's That? | Seattle, WA | April 2016 – current Node.js | Express.js | JavaScript | Swift

Early stage start-up that is building a mobile app that educates customers about potentially toxic ingredients in their food. Built originally with the MEAN stack and now converting to Swift and Node.JS.

- Wireframe design
- Tested and integrated external API to pull ingredient information.
- Currently re-designing landing page using HMTL, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query and Materialize CSS

Web Development Immersive Student

General Assembly | Seattle, WA | March 2016 - June 2016

12-week full-time immersive web development program developing fullstack web applications using various languages, frameworks, and libraries with a strong focus on JavaScript Frameworks, the MEAN stack and Ruby on Rails. Worked on group and individual projects using test driven development strategies and technologies.

Projects:

<u>Produce Exchange</u> - https://github.com/emilieg/produceexchange MongoDB | Express.js | AngularJS | Node.js | JavaScript | Cloudinary API A Craigslist like app for produce that helps neighbors trade their goods. Solo full stack project completed in 4 days.

- application includes user sign up, sign in and sign out functionality
- Node.JS framework and Express routes
- Cloudinary API to enable upload of pictures to the site
- MongoDB persists post data

EMILIE GERBER

WEB DEVELOPER

SKILLS

Responsive Web Design

Full Stack Web Apps

Deployment

Version Control (Git/GitHub)

PROJECTS & WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Wino911 - https://wino911.herokuapp.com/

PostgreSQL | Express.js | Node.js | JavaScript | Google Pl. & Directions API This app helps you find the closest place that serves wine. I used the user's current coordinates to find a wine bar and route directions using the Google Places and Directions API.

<u>Cappstone</u> - https://github.com/emilieg/cappstone

PostgreSQL | Ruby | Rails | JavaScript | Google OAuth | Google Calendar API An application that tracks all job search related activities. This app was built part of a group initiative with 3 other developers in 4 days. I was responsible for the design and front-end work, Google Calendar API and helped implement Google OAuth.

<u>Stuck in the Mud</u> - https://github.com/emilieg/stuck-in-the-mud JavaScript | HTML | CSS | jQuery | CSS Animations library Interactive dice game for two players competing for the highest score. This is a front-end only project where I focused on design, interactivity and game loop script.

Marketing & Research Coordinator

Seattle Times | Seattle, WA | July 2015 - January 2015

- Planned and promoted the Seattle Times LiveWire event series using Social Media and working with partners from local 500 companies.
- Worked with UX/UI team on landing page and ensured consistent branding
- Inaugural event attracted a 400 person audience

Marketing Coordinator

Measurement Technology NW & ECS | Seattle, WA | Nov. 2014 – July 2015

- Developed newsletters and email campaigns using MailChimp & Adobe Creative Tools
- Managed website content using Drupal
- Prepared Google Analytics reports and updated pages to improve SEO

Regional Account Manager

Pacific Interpreters | Portland, OR | February 2008 - November 2014

- Managed customer accounts with an average of \$700,000 monthly revenue.
- Increased customer revenue by 20% in 2012.
- Successfully project managed automation of client reporting system working closely with internal engineering team.